我不知道… 什么？
-Oh,I don't know. -What?
照狗的年纪来算…
Well,as old as he is in dog years...
你认为史奴比 还能飞这个玩意儿吗？
...do you think Snoopy should still be flying this thing?
瑞秋？
Rachel?
什么事？
Yeah?
记得你刚来的时候 有另外一个服务生训练你吗？
Remember when you first came here and you got trained by another waitress?
当然，要我训练新人吗？
Sure! Do you need me to train somebody new?
问得好
Good one.
其实是特瑞要你再受训一次
Actually,Terry wants you to take the training again.
什么时候都可以
Whenever.
你相信这种事吗？
Do you believe that?
相信
Yeah.
本集播出：“瑞秋辞职”
The One Where Rachel Quits
一共是两盒蛋白杏仁饼干
So that's two boxes of the Holiday Macaroons.
我代表美国棕鸟向你致敬
On behalf of the Brown Birds of America,I salute you.
承认吧，你不会反手击球
Just admit it. You have no backhand.
对不起，小鬼 我反手击球很厉害
Excuse me,little one. I have a very solid backhand.
像个女人一样掩面大叫…
Shielding your face and shrieking like a girl...
不叫反手击球
...is not a backhand.
我的叫声…
I was shrieking...
像海军
...Iike a Marine.
好，看我示范 冠军选手的三个P
All right,watch me execute the three P's of championship play.
力量…
Power...
精确…
... precision...
架式（都是以P开头的词）
...and panache.
你害一个小女孩的腿骨折？
You broke a little girl's leg?
我知道，我很难过，行吗？
I know. I feel horrible,okay?
报上说有个提线木偶昨晚在芝麻街遭遇重击
It says here that a Muppet got whacked on Sesame Street last night.
你昨晚十点左右人在哪里？
Where exactly were you around 10-ish?
我要去看她 我想带点东西给她
I'm going to see her. I wanna bring her something.
她会喜欢什么？ 凯蒂猫的玩偶？
-What would she like? -A Hello Kitty doll?
走路的能力？
The ability to walk?
我得回去接受再训练了
I'm gonna get back to retraining.
好，再见，各位
All right. See you,guys.
小心，小朋友，他来了
Look out,kids! He's coming!
我得去卖圣诞树了
I gotta go sell Christmas trees.
卖得开心点 等等，不要去
Have fun. Oh,wait! No,don't!
我忘了我现在完全反对这件事
I forgot. I am totally against that now.
什么？反对我有工作？
What? Me having a job?
不，我反对无辜的树木 在青春正盛的时候被砍下…
No,I am against innocent trees being cut down in their prime...
尸体被装饰得怪模怪样…
...and their corpses grotesquely dressed...
挂上一堆金箔和闪灯…
...in,like,tinsel and twinkly lights.
你昨晚睡得好吗？
How do you sleep at night?
我拖着树走来走去 累得要命
Well,I'm pretty tired from lugging the trees around.
你完全搞错了 那些树生来就是要当圣诞树的
You got this all wrong. Those trees were born to be Christmas trees.
为人们带来欢乐 是实现他们生存的目的
They're fulfilling their life purpose by making people happy.
真的？
Really?
没错！
Yes!
对，这些树也很高兴…
Yes,and the trees are happy too...
因为对大多数的树来说 这是他们…
...because for most of them,it's their only...
见识纽约的唯一机会
...chance to see New York.
送完饮料之后，把盘子…
After you deliver the drinks,take the tray
甘瑟，拜托 我在这里做了两年半
Gunther,please. I have worked here for two and a half years.
我知道空盘子要放在那里
I know the empty trays go over there.
放在这里怎么样？
What if you put them here?
这倒是个好主意 离马克杯比较近
That's actually a good idea. They'll be closer to the mugs.
你应该要其他的服务生照办
You should have the other waitresses do that too.
她们本来就是这么放的
They already do.
所以她们管这里叫盘子区
That's why they call it the tray spot.
我听到她们说这个 我还以为是她们参加的俱乐部
I heard them talk about that. I just thought it was a club they went to.
对不起 没关系
-I'm sorry. -It's all right.
甜心
Sweetheart.
你一定很高兴吧？
So this must be kind of neat for you,huh?
你爸爸说你可以不用上学
Your dad tells me you get school off...
也不必再去卖饼干了
...and you don't have to sell those cookies anymore.
我很想去卖饼干
I kind of wanted to sell the cookies.
卖最多饼干的人 可以免费参加太空营
Whoever sells the most wins a trip to Space Camp...
坐上真正的太空梭
...and gets to sit in a real shuttle.
你很喜欢太空的东西，是吧？
You really like all this space stuff,huh?
我爸爸说 如果我帮他清洁公寓的时间
My dad says if I'd spend as much time helping him clean apartments...
和我做太空梦的时间一样多
...as I do daydreaming about outer space...
他就可以去泰姬陵了
... he'd be able to afford a trip to the Taj Mahal.
要清洁很多间公寓 才有钱去印度
You'd have to clean a lot of apartments to go all the way to lndia.
不，是亚特兰大的泰姬陵王牌睹场 爸爸喜欢吃角子老虎
No. The one in Atlantic City. Dad loves the slots.
他说可以把祖母留给我的 大学学费再增加一倍
He says he'll double the college money Grandma left me.
那就祝爸爸好运吧
Well,good luck to Dad.
要卖多少盒饼干才能获胜？
Say,how many more boxes would you have to sell in order to win?
去年的冠军卖了475盒
The girl who won last year sold 475.
我到目前为止卖了75盒
So far,I've sold 75.
还有四百盒
Four hundred,huh?
应该不难，一盒多少钱？
Well,that sounds doable. How much are the boxes?
五块钱
Five dollars a box.
二等奖是什么？
And what is second prize?
十段变速脚踏车，但我宁可 要爸爸不能变卖的东西
A 10-speed bike. But I'd rather have something my dad couldn't sell.
这也对
Well,that makes sense.
帮我一个忙好吗？如果不太麻烦你的话
Could you do me one favor?lf it's not too much trouble.
好的，莎拉，随便什么事情
Yeah,Sarah. Anything.
你帮我把窗帘拉起来好吗？
Could you pull the curtains open?
太空人会上电视新闻
The shuttle astronauts are gonna be on the news.
我们没有电视，对面的小姐…
We don't have a TV,so the lady across the alley...
说她会把她的电视 推到窗口让我看
...said she'd push hers up to her window so I can watch it.
什么事？
Yes?
嗨，我是卖棕鸟饼干的
Hi. I'm selling Brown Bird cookies.
你不是棕鸟队员 我可以从窥视孔看到你
You're no Brown Bird. I can see you through my peephole.
嗨，我是棕鸟的荣誉队员
Hi. I'm an honorary Brown Bird.
这是什么意思？
What does that mean?
是说我可以卖饼干 但不能在别人家过夜
It means that I can sell cookies,but I'm not invited to sleepovers.
我可以按钮拨911报警
I can dial 911 at the press of a button,you know.
快走
Now,go away!
拜托…我是为了一个 贫穷的小女孩…
Please,please. It's for a poor little girl...
她最大的心愿就是参加太空营
...who wants to go to Space Camp more than anything in the world.
我要按钮了
I'm pressing.
警察马上就来了
A policeman is on his way.
好…我马上走
Okay,okay! I'm going,I'm going.
我还看得到你
I can still see you!
好啦！
All right!
你在这里干嘛？ 我把你的话想了很久
-What are you doing here? -I thought a lot about what you said...
我发觉也许我是有点太苛刻了
...and I realize maybe I was a little judgmental.
对，可是…
Yeah. Oh,but,oh.
菲比，记住…
Now,now,Phoebe,remember...
它们只是在实现它们的圣诞…
...they're just fulfilling their Christmas
宿命 没错
-Destiny. Yes. -Sure.
那棵看起来好像很空虚
That one doesn't look very fulfilled.
那是老树了 他只是把树拿到后面罢了
That's one of the old ones. He's just taking it to the back.
你们把老树放在后面？
You keep the old ones in the back?
真是年龄歧视
That is so ageist.
这样才有地方放新鲜的树
We're making room for the fresh ones.
那老的怎么办？
So what happens to the old guys?
拿去切碎
They go into the chipper.
我感觉好像不怎么快乐似的
I have a feeling that's not as happy as it sounds.
“中央咖啡厅”
这些是圣诞人物的形状
These are shaped like Christmas characters.
圣诞老人 鲁道夫，和耶稣宝宝
Santa,Rudolph and Baby Jesus.
我要一盒奶油馅的耶稣宝宝
I'll take a box of the cream-filled Jesuses.
一盒？这可是为了帮助 一个想参加太空营的小女孩呢
One box? I'm trying to send a little girl to Space Camp.
我算你五盒，你呢？
I'm putting you down for 5 boxes. What about you?
好吧，你有没有 椰子口味的神灵？
All right. Do you have any coconut-flavored deities?
没有，但光明节的蜡烛有椰子馅
No,but there's coconut in the Hanukkah Menorah-eos.
我算你八盒，一晚一盒
I'll put you down for 8 boxes. One for each night.
莫妮卡？
Mon?
我要一盒薄荷口味的
I'll take a box of the Mint Treasures.
一盒就好了
One,and that's it.
我参加棕鸟之后就胖了
I gained weight after I joined the Brown Birds.
记得吗？爸爸买光了 我的饼干，我全都吃掉了
Remember? Dad bought every one of my boxes and I ate them all.
不，莫妮卡，爸爸不得 不买下每一盒饼干…
No,Mon. Dad had to buy every one of your boxes...
是因为你把饼干吃光了
... because you ate them all.
可是这次一定不会这样了
But,you know,I'm sure that's not gonna happen this time.
我给你算三盒薄荷 两盒鲁道夫吧？
Why don't I put you down for 3 Mint Treasures and a couple of Rudolphs?
不要
No.
好啦，你知道你很想吃
Oh,come on,now. You know you want them.
不要这样
Don't do this.
这样吧，第一盒算我送的
I'll tell you what,I'll give you the first box for free.
老天，我得走了
Oh,God! I gotta go!
来嘛，好孩子都吃这种饼干
Come on! All the cool kids are eating them.
待会儿新的服务生来了 我会告诉你为什么不能…
And later,I'll show you why we don't just trap spiders...
把蜘蛛困在马克杯底下就算了
... under coffee mugs and leave them there.
我痛恨这工作，还要努力改进 我的人生算是完了
I'm training to be better at a job that I hate. My life officially sucks!
这不是暂时性的工作而已吗？ 你的目标是打入时装界
Wasn't this supposed to be temporary? You wanted to do fashion stuff.
对，我还在朝目标前进
Yeah,I'm still pursuing that.
你是怎么前进的？
How,exactly,are you pursuing that?
两年前寄寄履历表吗？
Other than sending out resumes,like,what? Two years ago?
我还传达了…
Well,I'm also sending out...
好点子
...good thoughts.
如果你问我意见的话，只要你还有这份工作
If you ask me,as long as you got this job...
就没有找新工作的动机
...you got nothing pushing you to get another one.
你需要的是恐惧
You need The Fear.
恐惧？ 他说得对
-The Fear? -He's right.
辞掉这份工作，才有动机 追求你心目中理想的工作
Quit this job,and you'll have motivation to go after a job you really want.
你为何还在做你讨厌的工作？ 干嘛不辞职来产生恐惧
Why are you still at a job you hate? Why don't you quit and get The Fear?
因为我太害怕了
Because I'm too afraid.
我不知道，我愿意不计一切 为设计师或采购人工作
I don't know. I'd give anything to work for a designer or a buyer.
我不想到了30岁 还在这里工作
I just don't want to be 30 and still work here.
对，那要比28岁 还在这里工作惨多了
Yeah,that'd be much worse than being 28 and still working here.
瑞秋，提醒我跟你复习 哪壶是低咖啡因的，哪壶不是
Remind me to review with you which pot is decaf and which is regular.
看把手看不出来吗？
Can't I just look at the handles on them?
想得美
You would think.
好了，甘瑟，你知道吗？ 我是个很差劲的服务生
Okay,fine. Gunther,you know what? I am a terrible waitress.
你知道这是为什么吗？ 因为我不在乎
Do you know why I'm a terrible waitress? Because I don't care.
我不在乎哪壶是普通咖啡 哪壶是低咖啡因
I don't care which pot is regular and which pot is decaf.
我不在乎盘子区在哪里
I don't care where the tray spot is.
我就是不在乎 这不是我想做的工作
I just don't care. This is not what I want to do.
所以我想我不该再做下去了
So I don't think I should do it anymore.
我要提出我的星期通告（如果辞职需要提前一周说明） 什么？
-I'm giving my week's notice. -What?
甘瑟，我辞职
Gunther,I quit.
这表示以后喝咖啡 要付钱了吗？
Does this mean we have to start paying for coffee?
好，12，22，18
Okay,twelve.Twenty-two.Eighteen.
干嘛？
What?
我拼出了“乳房”（5318008的倒置）
I spelled out "boobies".
再给我一盒 薄荷口味的，好吗？
Put me down for another box of the Mint Treasures,okay?
薄荷饼干在哪里？
Where are the Mint Treasures?
没有了，都卖光了
We're out. I sold them all.
什么？
What?
莫妮卡 我不能再让你吃下去了
Monica,I'm cutting you off.
再两盒就好
Just a couple more boxes.
这也没什么，我很好
It's no big deal,all right? I'm cool.
你得帮我再弄两盒
You gotta help me with a couple more boxes!
看看你自己 你脖子上还有饼干
Look at yourself. You have cookie on your neck.
老天！
Oh,God!
你卖了几盒？ 你看
-So how many you sold so far? -Check this out.
417盒 老天，你怎么办到的？
-Five hundred and seventeen boxes! -Oh,my God! How did you do that?
前两天晚上 我离开博物馆的时候
The other night I was leaving the museum...
天文馆正在放激光佛洛依德
...just as Laser Floyd was letting out of the planetarium.
我随随便便就卖了五十盒
Without even trying,I sold 50 boxes!
这时我想到成功的关键就是 “饥饿感”
That's when it occurred to me. The key to my success: The munchies.
所以我开始在午夜时分 到纽约大学的宿舍去
So I started hitting the NYU dorms around midnight.
我把饼干论箱卖
I am selling cookies by the case.
他们叫我“饼干佬”
They call me "Cookie Dude"!
-很好，但是我不会那么叫你的 -好的
-Okay, but l'm not going to call you that.-Okay.
放下手边的事，我需要人 帮我塞信封、舔邮票…
Stop what you're doing. I need envelope stuffers,stamp lickers....
谁帮你写履历表的？ 我用我的电脑写的
-Who did these resumes for you? -Me. On my computer.
你还真用了够大号的黑体字
You sure used a large font.
对，“咖啡厅的服务生”…
Yeah. Well,"Waitress at a Coffeehouse"...
和啦啦队队长 占不了多少空间
...and "Cheer Squad Co-Captain" only took up so much room.
真有趣
Hey,that's funny!
你好有趣，钱德 你有趣极了
You're funny,Chandler! You're a funny guy!
知道还有哪件事也很有趣吗？
You know what else is funny?
我说错了什么吗？
Something else I might have said?
我不知道 不是你在我毫无后路的时候…
I don't know. Weren't you the guy that told me to quit my job...
叫我辞职的吗？
...when I had absolutely nothing else to do?
别激动，事情会顺利的
Calm down. It's gonna be okay.
不，不会的 明天是我最后一天上班
No,it's not gonna be okay. Tomorrow is my last day...
而我到现在还毫无进展
...and I don't have a lead.
你知道吗？ 我要打电话给甘瑟
You know what? I'm just gonna call Gunther...
说我不辞职了
...and tell him I'm not quitting.
你不能向恐惧投降
You don't want to give in to The Fear.
你和你愚蠢的恐惧 我痛恨你的恐惧
You and your stupid Fear! I hate your Fear!
我要把你和你的恐惧…
I would like to take you and your Fear
嘿，我有好消息
Hey! I got great news!
快跑，乔伊，逃命去吧
Run,Joey! Run for your life!
干嘛？瑞秋，听好了 你听过福图那塔时装没有？
What? Rach,listen. Have you ever heard of Fortunata Fashions?
我老爸在那里做水电工 听说那里要找人
My dad's got a plumbing job there and he heard there's an opening.
要他帮你安排面试吗？
You want him to get you an interview?
天哪，我要，太好了 你好可爱，乔伊
Oh,my God,yes! I would love that! That's so sweet,Joey.
小事一桩
Not a problem.
现在告诉你们好消息
And now,for the great news.
刚才那个不是好消息？
That wasn't the great news?
除非你们觉得比这个消息更好
Only if you think it's better than this.
喷雪！
Snow-in-a-Can!
要我装饰窗户吗？
You want me to decorate the window?
看起来有圣诞的感觉
Give it kind of a Christmas looky?
圣诞饼干？
Christmas cookie?
好，这是一棵道格拉斯枞树
Okay,and this one here's a Douglas fir.
这个比较贵一点，但也比较香
Now,it's a little more money,but you get a nicer smell.
看起来不错，我买了
Looks good. I'll take it.
等等，不要 不要买那棵
Wait,wait. No,no! You don't want that one!
不，你可以买这棵棕色的树
No,no. You can have this cool brown one.
这树都快死了
It's almost dead.
所以非买不可 让它完成它的圣诞宿命
That's why you have to buy it,to fulfill its Christmas destiny.
不然他们就会把它拿去切碎 告诉他
Otherwise,they'll throw it into the chipper. Tell him.
对，无法完成圣诞宿命的树
Yeah,the trees that don't fulfill their Christmas destiny...
就要拿去切碎
...are thrown in the chipper.
我还是再看看吧
I think I'm gonna look around a little bit more.
你不能再这样搞下去了 我是赚佣金的
You gotta stop doing this. I'm working on commission here!
我来挑一棵圣诞树
I'm here to pick out my Christmas tree.
别看了，就买这棵
Well,look no further! This one's yours!
这是我去年丢掉的树吗？
Is this the one that I threw out last year?
算了，大家都想买绿树
Never mind! Everybody wants a green one!
对不起，我也不想这么情绪化
I'm sorry. I didn't mean to get so emotional.
过节就是让人很难受
The holidays are just hard.
亲爱的，这是因为 你母亲在圣诞节前后过世吗？
Oh,honey. Is that because your mom died around Christmas?
我还没想到那件事呢
I wasn't even thinking about that.
嗨，你卖了多少？
Hi there. How many did you sell?
我不告诉你 你是害莎拉断腿的坏人
I'm not gonna tell you. You're the bad man who broke Sarah's leg.
嘿，那是意外，好吗？
Hey,now. That was an accident,okay?
你是个大斗蛋
You're a big scrud.
什么叫斗蛋？
What's a scrud?
照镜子就看到了，斗蛋
Why don't you look in the mirror,scrud?
我不用照镜子 我看你就行了
I don't have to. I can just look at you.
好，各位小女孩…
All right,girls...
和大男人
...and man.
我们看看大家的总成绩
Let's see your final tallies.
黛比
Debbie.
321盒饼干，很好
Three hundred and twenty-one boxes of cookies. Very nice.
还不够好
Not nice enough.
夏拉
Charla.
278盒
Two hundred and seventy-eight.
对不起，亲爱的 但还是不错
Sorry,dear,but still good.
对斗蛋来说是不错
Good for a scrud.
你呢，伊莉莎白？
Yes,Elizabeth.
871盒
Eight hundred and seventy-one.
胡扯
That's crap!
棕鸟修女
Sister Brown Bird.
做得好
Good going.
下一个是谁？
Who's next?
嗨 嗨
-Hi there. -Hi.
替代莎拉的…
And batting for Sarah...
罗斯盖勒
... Ross Geller.
872盒
Eight hundred and seventy-two.
不过看样子 你自己买了一大堆饼干
Although,it looks like you bought an awful lot of cookies yourself.
那是因为我的医生说我有…
That is because my doctor says that I have...
很严重的…
...a very serious...
果仁糖…
... nougat...
不足…
...deficiency.
把事情的经过告诉我们 棕鸟罗斯
Tell us what happened,Brown Bird Ross.
我输了，有个小女孩 把制服借给19岁的姐姐
I lost. Some little girl loaned her uniform to her 19-year-old sister...
她到美国轮船尼米兹号… 卖掉了两千多盒
...who went down to the U. S. S. Nimitz and sold over 2000 boxes.
面试怎么样？ 我搞砸了
-How'd the interview go? -Oh,I blew it.
连我自己都不会请我
I wouldn't have even hired me.
过来，甜心
Come here,sweetie.
听我说…
Listen...
找到工作之前 要应征一千次…
...you're gonna go on,like,1000 interviews before you get a job.
这种情形应该不会发生
That's not how that was supposed to come out.
这是最糟糕的圣诞节
This is just the worst Christmas ever.
也许你应该留在咖啡厅
Maybe you should just stay here at the coffeehouse.
不行了，太迟了 特瑞已经请了那个女孩
I can't. It's too late. Terry already hired that girl over there.
你们看看她
Look at her.
她还有当服务生的经验
She's even got waitress experience.
昨天晚上，她还…
Last night she was...
教大家把…
...teaching everybody how to make...
餐巾…
... napkins...
折成…
...into....
她说的是“天鹅”
That word was "swans."
看到酒醉的圣诞老人尿湿了自己 我的圣诞节可真快乐
Well,seeing that drunk Santa wet himself really perked up my Christmas.
我的天
Oh,my God!
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas!
你们救了他们…
You saved them! You guys!
老天，你们太棒了
Oh,God,you're the best!
好像是《活死人之夜》的圣诞树（1968年的第一部僵尸片）
Looks like Night of the Living Dead Christmas Trees.
对，我就是
Yeah,this is she.
你开玩笑…
You're kidding! You're kidding!
谢谢，我爱你
Oh,thank you! I love you!
当然啦 大家都爱开玩笑的人
Sure,everybody loves a kidder.
我找到工作了
I got the job!
太好了
That's great.
上帝保佑我们大家
God bless us,everyone!
来，这是我最后一次端咖啡
Here we go. I'm serving my last cup of coffee.
来
There you go.
用心品尝吧
Enjoy.
我该告诉她我点的是茶吗？ 不要说
-Should I tell her I ordered tea? -No.
对不起，各位？
Excuse me,everyone?
这是我在这里 工作的最后一夜…
This is my last night working here...
我只想说…
...and I just wanted to say...
我在这里交了一些好朋友…
...that I made some good friends here.
现在是向前走的时候了
And it's just time to move on.
我无意冒犯 各位留在这里的人
And no offense to everybody who still works here...
但你们不知道我多庆幸…
... but you have no idea how good it feels to say...
可以在这一刻说…
...that as of this moment...
我再也不必冲咖啡了…
... I will never have to make coffee again.
老卡普兰先生喜欢喝浓咖啡
Now,Mr. IKaplan Sr. Iikes his coffee strong.
所以一包不够，要用两包
So you want to use two bags instead of one.
注意听好了，这里很需要技巧
Now,pay attention. This part's tricky.
有些人的滤纸只用一次
See,some people use filters just once....
我很遗憾你不能参加太空营
I'm sorry you didn't get to go to Space Camp...
我希望这个或许 能帮我补偿你，好吗？
...and I'm hoping that maybe somehow this may help make up for it. Okay?
接下来是…
Presenting...
莎拉图多的私人特制太空营
...Sarah Tuddle's Private Very Special Space Camp!
你不必这么做的
You don't have to do this.
别客气，来吧
Oh,come on,here we go!
准备倒数
Stand by for mission countdown!
十
Ten.
九
Nine.
八
Eight.
好，发射
Okay,blast off!
我是外星人…
I'm an alien! I'm an alien!
不，小行星来了
Oh,no! An asteroid!